Naufal Nashif Imanuddin

Bogor, 16680, Indonesia | +62895422445605 | naufalnashif.imanuddin@gmail.com

LINKS

Website | LinkedIn | Github | Instagram | Twitter | Huggingface

SUMMARY

A 22-year-old data enthusiast, and I hold a Bachelor's degree in Statistics and Data Science from IPB University. With over 2 years of experience, I specialize in machine learning, web development, and systematic data collection, utilizing tools such as Python, Golang, MySql, MongoDB, Github, Streamlit, RegEx, Html, and Css.

EDUCATION

IPB University | Bachelor's degree, Statistics and Data Science

August 2019 – January 2024

I have completed my bachelor's degree, focusing my research on the creation of a Natural Language Processing (NLP) model designed for sentiment analysis. Additionally, I implemented this model by developing a web application for practical use. My organizational experiences:

• Head of Media and Branding Division at Junior Statistics Competition

January 2022 – October 2022

• Staff of Media and Branding Division at Departmental Student Association

October 2021 – October 2022

PROJECTS

Build End to End Machine Learning NLP Sentiment Analysis Web Application

Tools: Python, Snscrape, Scikit-learn, RegEx, NLTK, Streamlit, Huggingface

Links: Repository | Demo

- Scraping +4000 tweets from Twitter
- Data preprocessing (labeling, data cleaning, slang normalization, stopwords removal, stemming, tokenizing, Tf
 Idf, and Smote)
- Exploratory data analysis (sentiment class distribution, sentiment timeline, and wordclouds)
- Build ensemble model with three base classifiers (Multinomial Logistic Regression, Multinomial Naïve Bayes, and Random Forest)
- Model deployment (using Streamlit framework and deploy on Huggingface)

Build Portfolio Website

Tools: Vscode, Html, Css, Javascript, Github, Netlify platform

Links: Repository | Demo

EXPERIENCES

Backend Engineer - Bootcamp at PT Ruang Raya Indonesia

January 2023 – July 2023

- Basic Frontend with Html, Css, Js and Tailwind
- Backend with Go programming language
- Databases with Sql and NoSql
- APIs testing with Postman
- Version Control with Git and Github

Data Specialist at PT. Xquisite AI

September 2022 – December 2022

- Specialized in Python-based OCR for PDF data extraction and conversion.
- Key role in Azure Databricks data rollout.
- Contributed to Power BI dashboard modifications.
- Conducted User Acceptance Testing (UAT) for dashboard accuracy and usability.
- Enhanced skills in data manipulation, visualization, data engineering and business intelligence.

LANGUAGES

Indonesian (native spreaker)

English (very good command)